<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>president on home</title>
    <link>/categories/president/</link>
    <description>Recent content in president on home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/categories/president/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Night at the American Museum of Natural History: Dr. Sean Decatur</title>
      <link>/blog/episode49/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/episode49/</guid>
      <description>In this episode, I interviewed Dr. Sean Decatur, the President of the American Museum of Natural History (AMNH) with my lab&amp;rsquo;s amazing manager, Sylvie Parkus. It was inspiring listening to his story about wanting to diversify the scientific workforce.
Transcription Transcription available upon request</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Authenticity &amp; Moving the Culture of Science Forward: Dr. Raven Baxter</title>
      <link>/blog/episode48/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/episode48/</guid>
      <description>In this episode, I interviewed Dr. Raven Baxter, otherwise known as Raven the Science Maven. She is a prominent scientist, science communicator, and STEM educator. She is also the President of the The Science Haven.
Transcription Transcribed by Cami Brousse (she/her)
JP Flores (he/him): Cool. So I usually start this off with an autobiography. So do you mind telling me, you know, your name? Your educational journey, scientific journey, and where you are now.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Trust in Science Requires Diversity: Dr. Freeman Hrabowski</title>
      <link>/blog/episode46/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/episode46/</guid>
      <description>In this episode, I interviewed Dr. Freeman Hrabowski, the President Emeritus of The University of Maryland, Baltimore County (UMBC).
Per his website: He has given numerous TED talks and chaired the National Academies’ committee that produced the report, Expanding Underrepresented Minority Participation: America’s Science and Technology Talent at the Crossroads. President Obama named him chair of the President’s Advisory Commission on Educational Excellence for African Americans in 2012.
In 1988, he co-founded the Meyerhoff Scholars Program.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
