<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>science-communication on home</title>
    <link>/categories/science-communication/</link>
    <description>Recent content in science-communication on home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/categories/science-communication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Representation Matters: Dr. Andre Isaacs</title>
      <link>/blog/episode52/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/episode52/</guid>
      <description>In this episode, Dr. Zack Drum, a postdoc in my lab, and I interviewed Dr. Andre Isaacs.
Andre is originally from Jamaica and moved to the US to attend College of the Holy Cross, where he received his BA in Chemistry. He then went on to pursue his PhD at the University of Pennsylvania and his postdoctoral training at University of California, Berkeley. Currently, he is an Associate Professor at College of the Holy Cross.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Makes a &#39;Good&#39; Scientist? : Dr. Roshni Patel &amp; Dr. Rachel Ungar</title>
      <link>/blog/episode51/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/episode51/</guid>
      <description>In this episode, I interviewed Dr. Roshni Patel &amp;amp; Dr. Rachel Ungar. As graduate students at Stanford University in the Pritchard and Montgomery labs, respectively, they created a genetics &amp;amp; ethics course and published about it! Check it out here:
⁠Increasing equity in science requires better ethics training: A course by trainees, for trainees
Course content can be found here.
Transcription Transcribed by Jayati Sharma (she/her)
JP Flores (he/him): So if you listen to this I think you&amp;rsquo;ll know that I start these off with a short autobiographies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Science is Fallible: Angela Saini</title>
      <link>/blog/episode50/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/episode50/</guid>
      <description>In this episode, I interviewed Angela Saini with Dr. Mike Love. Angela is a prominent author interested in bridging science and society. Her works include the fantastic books:
⁠Inferior: How Science Got Women Wrong and the New Research That’s Rewriting the Story ⁠⁠Superior: The Return of Race Science ⁠The Patriarchs: The Origins of Inequality Transcription Transcription rendered by Zoom
Angela Saini: Yeah. My name&amp;rsquo;s Angela Saney. I&amp;rsquo;m a science journalist and author Right now, I teach science writing at MIT, and I&amp;rsquo;m a Moynihan public scholar at CCNY until the end of next year.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Night at the American Museum of Natural History: Dr. Sean Decatur</title>
      <link>/blog/episode49/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/episode49/</guid>
      <description>In this episode, I interviewed Dr. Sean Decatur, the President of the American Museum of Natural History (AMNH) with my lab&amp;rsquo;s amazing manager, Sylvie Parkus. It was inspiring listening to his story about wanting to diversify the scientific workforce.
Transcription Transcription available upon request</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Authenticity &amp; Moving the Culture of Science Forward: Dr. Raven Baxter</title>
      <link>/blog/episode48/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/episode48/</guid>
      <description>In this episode, I interviewed Dr. Raven Baxter, otherwise known as Raven the Science Maven. She is a prominent scientist, science communicator, and STEM educator. She is also the President of the The Science Haven.
Transcription Transcribed by Cami Brousse (she/her)
JP Flores (he/him): Cool. So I usually start this off with an autobiography. So do you mind telling me, you know, your name? Your educational journey, scientific journey, and where you are now.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diversity in Shark Science: Jasmin Graham</title>
      <link>/blog/episode4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/episode4/</guid>
      <description>In this episode, I was able to interview Jasmin Graham who is a shark scientist studying elasmobranch ecology and evolution. She has a passion for science education and making science more accessible for everyone, especially underrepresented minority students. She is a director of the MarSci-LACE project and one of the CEOs of the Minorities in Shark Science (MISS). Enjoy!
Transcription Transcribed by Stephanie Peak (she/her)
JP: What&amp;rsquo;s up y&amp;rsquo;all? It&amp;rsquo;s your host, JP Flores, and welcome to the fifth episode of &amp;ldquo;From Where Does it STEM?</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
