<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>government-scientist on home</title>
    <link>/categories/government-scientist/</link>
    <description>Recent content in government-scientist on home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/categories/government-scientist/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Empowering Women in STEM: Dr. Marcia McNutt</title>
      <link>/blog/episode43/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/episode43/</guid>
      <description>In this episode, I chatted with Dr. Marcia McNutt. A decorated scientist who was the 15th Director (and 1st woman) of the United States Geological Survey (USGS), the President and CEO of the Monterey Bay Aquarium Research Institute (MBARI), a Professor of Marine Geophysics at Stanford University and UC Santa Cruz, and a Professor of Geophysics at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT). She was also the science adviser to the United States Secretary of the Interior, and the former Editor-In-Chief of Science Magazine.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hearing it from the Top: Dr. Neali Lucas</title>
      <link>/blog/episode37/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/episode37/</guid>
      <description>In this episode, I interviewed Dr. Neali Lucas. She has been at the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) for 14 years, where she is currently the Senior Science Advisor in the Office of the Commissioner, Office of the Chief Scientist. She was the first African-American scientist to graduate from her graduate program at the University of Michigan in 2007, and we had a rich discussion about equity and inclusion in STEM and the importance of hearing about how important these topics are from the top.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Directing the NHGRI : Dr. Eric Green</title>
      <link>/blog/episode30/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/episode30/</guid>
      <description>In this episode, I co-hosted Dr. Eric Green, Director of the NHGRI with Parth and Chinmay, the co-hosts of Biocast. He is the third NHGRI director, having been appointed by NIH director Dr. Francis Collins in 2009. In this episode, we talked about mentorship, baseball, and what it&amp;rsquo;s like to head an institute of the NIH.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-Gen Feels: Dr. Charles Scaife</title>
      <link>/blog/episode10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/episode10/</guid>
      <description>Episode 2 of Season 2 is LIVE! On this week’s episode, I had the opportunity to sit down and chat with Dr. Charles Scaife! Charles is currently an ORISE/ORAU Science, Technology, and Policy Fellow at the US Dept. of Energy and was formerly a NOAA Sea Grant Knauss Fellow! He received his PhD from the University of Virginia and completed his undergrad at UNC Chapel Hill! Enjoy!</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
