<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>postdoc on home</title>
    <link>/categories/postdoc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in postdoc on home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/categories/postdoc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building Science Community through Social Media: Dr. Ubadah Sabbagh &amp; Dr. Daniel Gonzales</title>
      <link>/blog/episode31/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/episode31/</guid>
      <description>In this episode, I interviewed Dr. Ubadah Sabbagh &amp;amp; Dr. Daniel Gonzales. Ubadah is a Syrian neuroscientist and NIH K00 Fellow at the McGovern Institute for Brain Research at MIT, and Daniel just started a faculty position at Vanderbilt University in the Department of Biomedical Engineering. They met over social media, are freakin&amp;rsquo; HILARIOUS, and I am so glad I got to put them together in a Zoom room!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mentorship Matters: Yeraldi Loera</title>
      <link>/blog/episode16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/episode16/</guid>
      <description>Yeraldi Loera graduated from Occidental College as a Biology major in the Fall of 2016. After graduating, she attended California State Polytechnic University in Pomona for a Master’s in Biology. Since receiving her Master’s in 2019, she has started a PhD program in the department of Ecology and Evolutionary Biology at Princeton University in the lab of Dr. Shane Campbell-Staton. She emphasizes her gratitude to do what she loves and is outspoken on connecting with others about their obstacles and journeys.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Military Brat and Kicking Balls to Cancer Research: Dr. Alexis Zukowski </title>
      <link>/blog/episode8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/episode8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;the road less traveled by, and that has made all the difference.&amp;rdquo; Alexis Zukowski is a postdoc in the lab of Dr.Srinivas Ramachandran lab at the University of Colorado, Denver- Anschutz Medical Campus.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
